<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>a Backend Engineer</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on a Backend Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 04:32:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to start a programming blog in Nigeria (2018)</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-start-a-programming-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 04:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-start-a-programming-blog/</guid>
      <description>Are you a web developer? looking forward to start your own programming blog. Or maybe you&amp;rsquo;re wondering how can a developer do blogging.
Some developers don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of blogging. But as a software developer in Nigeria, or anywhere in the world. One of the best things you can do to accelerate your carrier, is to start publishing blog post.
Blogging has always been the best way to get your content out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Blogging Tools for Web developers</title>
      <link>/posts/best-blogging-platform-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/best-blogging-platform-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>If you ask me today. When is the best time to blog as a developer, I will say, Now.
I first heard the word &amp;ldquo;blog&amp;rdquo; in 2014. But I really don&amp;rsquo;t know what it is, nor how it works. Though I was interested in giving out my content to people so they could read the few things I know.
There&amp;rsquo;s something good knowing you have a book with several pages hosted on the internet, where you share everything you learn in your day to day life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 05:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>As a freelance web developer, I will love to hear from you.
Need a website? or want to work with me. You can chat me up on Telegram.
I am also on twitter.
Feel free to ask me any question on web development. I will love to help.
For all other inquiries, send me a mail.
Ikwuje24@gmail.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Jeremiah Succeed</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 05:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>A Web developer in Abuja with deep experience on web data and APIs. I build and design modern websites with different tools, mostly JavaScript and PHP. Just to let you know, I do create and sell website components.
I write on modern web development and the good things. If you like the contents on this blog, I encourage you to join my mailing list to get my fresh contents.
Need a website?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Check empty input in Javascript</title>
      <link>/posts/empty-input-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 15:38:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/empty-input-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>If you search on the internet on how to prevent a user from submitting empty data on a form, what you will mostly find is this.
var input = document.getElementById(&#39;user_input&#39;); if ( input.value == &amp;quot;&amp;quot; ) { alert(&amp;quot;Empty&amp;quot;); }  Now, while this work in most case, it&amp;rsquo;s only half the solution. The problem with this is that it sees white space as a data. Remember in computer science space is consider a character, though invisible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node.js - How to display content in HTML format</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-display-html-content-on-nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 09:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-display-html-content-on-nodejs/</guid>
      <description>I think this is my second post on Node.js.
In this post we are going to see how to display contents in HTML on a browser with Node.js.
Let’s start by creating a directory ( folder ) where our program will live. I’m going to call this directory project2, since it is our second project.
$ mkdir project2  Navigate to the folder you just created.
$ cd project2  Now inside the folder create a new file, name it app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get the total numbers of Files in a Folder with Node.js</title>
      <link>/posts/numbers-of-files-in-a-folder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 01:05:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/numbers-of-files-in-a-folder/</guid>
      <description>When working with files and directories in Node.js, the built in fs module provides an api for interacting with the file system. All file system have asynchronous and synchronous nature.
The fs module comes with a method readadir that enable Node.js to read the content in a directory.
The code below get the total number of files in a directory.
var fs = require(&#39;fs&#39;); fs.readdir ( &#39;path/to/your/folder&#39;, (error, files) =&amp;gt; { let totalFiles = files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node.Js - Your first web application</title>
      <link>/posts/writing-your-first-program-nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 15:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/writing-your-first-program-nodejs/</guid>
      <description>Some basic knowledge of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript will be good for you.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what is Node.js. Node.js is framework use for writing server side application with JavaScript. This means that you can writes a complete web application with only JavaScript. With Node.js you don&amp;rsquo;t need to write web applications using different web enable languages. With just a single language, you can do both the front and the back things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>